{
    "id": "128691df151b4ab09a88feebdef54a1b",
    "title": "Simple Past vs. Present Perfect",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I .................................. read a lot of books when I was at university.",
            "description": "We use used to to talk about past habits.",
            "answers": [
                "have read",
                "used to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She .................................... yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "called",
                "has called"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ..................................... unhappy since she left her parental home.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was a child, I ……………………. with my grandparents.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "lived",
                "used to live",
                "have lived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………. a new car yesterday.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
            "answers": [
                "bought",
                "has bought"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The injured child ……………………….. to hospital.",
            "description": "Was taken is the passive form of took. We use the passive verb here because the subject is not the doer of the action.",
            "answers": [
                "took",
                "was taken",
                "has taken"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Janet ………………………. her job. She is now struggling to make both ends meet.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to talk about a finished event whose effect is still felt in the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "lost",
                "has lost",
                "had lost"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. my arm while playing football yesterday.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "broke",
                "have broken"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They …………………………. the dog from the pit.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "rescued",
                "have rescued",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… from her since January.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "did not hear",
                "have not heard"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Everybody …………………………. the winning team.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "congratulated",
                "has congratulated",
                "have congratulated"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "All the students …………………………… in their work.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "handed",
                "have handed",
                "had handed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}